kettle bells are one of the most
functional training tools you could have
since any given workout is going to be
great for building muscle but it's also
going to double as a cardio workout
since your whole body is typically
involved with Nike making its presence
felt in the fitness industry I honestly
had no choice but to scoop up one of
their kettle bells so today this is
exactly what I'm going to be breaking
down for yall these range from 9 to 88
lbs and they have a nice powder coat
finish but are they worth the money
stick around and we'll find
out
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to be breaking down
Nike's brand new kettle bells if you're
new to this whole process in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about these kettle
bells from the price some things I like
and don't like but then of course who
should or maybe should not purchase
these before I do all of that though
just want to make sure you guys know
that we've reviewed a ton of kettlebells
and barb. and guess what we have our own
best list if you want to check that out
all you got to do is search barbend best
kettle bells it's going to pull right up
for you and you can find out for
yourself which ones we like the
best now typically in my videos I have
more Pros than I do cons but that's
actually the opposite here with these
kettle bells all right so for me the
best things about these are the weight
range which is from 9 to 88 lbs that's
plenty for most home gym athletes
obviously if you need more than that
you're going to have to go elsewhere
that's still a pretty solid range and
then the powder coat finish gives me a
really solid grip as I'm going to do my
workouts and that's definitely something
that you want whenever you're swinging
one of these funky shaped you know
objects around your home gym also you
know I thought it was pretty impressive
what Nike did with their packaging you
know I talked about this in another
video but they basically you know put
the kettle bell around styrofoam within
a box within another box and had extra
cardboard around that bigger box so they
really tried but to no avail because on
the back right here you know you can see
there's a big chunk missing right here
in that powder coat so I mean it's
probably more so on the actual delivery
and and everything in transit than it is
against Nike but that's definitely
something that you don't want to see the
construction overall here is not the
best in my opinion I think they could
have done a little bit better it
definitely doesn't seem to be a gravity
cast Bell where basically you're just
pouring you know the cast iron into a
mold and letting gravity you know take
care of business I guess you could say
it definitely doesn't seem that way here
all right so you have a seam a pretty
noticeable seam right here on the side
the bottom right here is not completely
finished there's some blemishes right
here doesn't look perfect like I've seen
with plenty of other kettle bells and
then also right here where the handle
actually connects to the Bell
you can see a bit of a seam right there
as well and it almost looks as if this
was welded so that's why I'm saying it
doesn't seem as if it was a gravity cast
kettle bell now this could be you know
only with this one right here I highly
doubt that but you know that could be
you know just my personal situation that
I'm in and then also with these kettle
bells they have a plusus 3% weight
accuracy so I'm going to weigh this
kettle bell in a second and see exactly
what we're working with and then lastly
here not too crazy about The Branding I
know that's sounds pretty nitpicky but
you know once you put this kettle bell
in the rack position you'll know what
I'm talking about so most companies with
their branding it's actually you know
recessed into the kettle bell it's
actually the opposite here with Nike so
everything is raised up and it's not
really something that you want all right
so first time I went to go and you know
do a clean with this kettle bell and put
it in that rack position the Nike logo
right here honestly it it dug into my
skin and kind of Twisted it really
didn't feel well at all I actually sat
here like ow I'm by myself so it's not
something that you want the back isn't
as bad but you don't want to have to be
you know conscious every single time
you're doing a kettle bell workout to
make sure that this is not going to be
digging into your arm so that could
definitely be improved in my
[Music]
opinion all right so regarding money
let's talk about the 9 lb Bell it's
going to cost you about 40 bucks this 53
lb Bell right here it's about $100 and
then the 88lb Bell is about 160 bucks
now shipping is definitely going to come
into factor with that it's usually 40
bucks or so right now they're doing a
50% off discount so it's going to cost
you about 20 additional dollars now as
far as the actual price goes it's pretty
competitive honestly it's actually very
competitive against the rest of the
market but kind of getting what you're
paying for right so with kettle bell
Kings their 53lb baell is going to cost
you around 136 bucks now shipping is
free but obviously you know more
expensive than this one but in my
opinion that extra money is worth it
because they do a really good job of you
know rejecting kettle bells that aren't
perfect in their eyes and this isn't the
case as you know with this kettle bell
right here there's some blemishes and
there's things I'm not too crazy about
so you're definitely getting what you're
paying for now if you want to go down
the best budget friendly route you could
I would definitely suggest going after
an adjustable kettle bell system they're
not going to be as heavy as you know you
can get with you know individual kettle
bell
but in the long run it's going to save
you money some of my favorites right now
are from rep Fitness so definitely go
and check those
out all right so right here on the front
as you see it's where you have your logo
labeling whatever you want to call it I
really wish this was recessed into the
actual kettle bell I'm not crazy about
how it sticks up it's not comfortable on
your arm that's just something that I
personally don't like also don't like
the amount of blemishes I'm seeing here
you know with any equipment I want it to
be perfect right you're spending your
hard-earned money on on something it
should come out the way you want it to
and this kable probably should have been
rejected but it is what it is I guess I
mean as you can I don't know if you can
see but there's a pretty noticeable seam
right here especially as you go to feel
it from the bottom honestly it looks
like it goes all the way up and down and
around so that's something that you
don't really want to find you know you
also got this big chunk missing from
transit right there that's something
that you also don't want as I was
talking about this earlier you know
you've got your labeling back here as
well it doesn't stick up as bad as the
front but it's still not very
comfortable on your skin and then on the
bottom right here I don't know if you
can tell or not but you've also got some
imperfections and that's something that
you don't really want on the base of a
kettle bell now the actual window right
here this is about 6 in maybe a shade
over 6.2 or something like that and then
the actual handle right here it's about
you know an inch and a half that's
pretty average with the 53lb kettle bell
now unfortunately they do not have a
ring chart on their website so you're
going to kind of have to figure out the
rest on your own remember this is a 53lb
kettle bell but they also mentioned on
their website they have a plusus 3%
weight accuracy so we're going to wait
it see what we're working with right
here with my trusty
scale
54.1 that's honestly that's fine that's
not that bad I've seen some 53 lb Bells
be 55
lb you definitely want it to be a
pinpoint accurate as possible but one lb
that's not too much to gripe over so if
you're really into Nike you might really
enjoy these kettle bells and they're
available at a pretty solid price point
compared to the rest of the competition
but that's because of the quality in my
opinion you know if you're wanting a
better quality product then I think you
should look elsewhere I mean this could
be just based off this one Kettle bill
you know but from what I'm seeing I'm
just not too crazy about and then
there's a whole lot of personal
preference here here as well if you need
more than 88 lbs You're simply not going
to get that here go elsewhere you know
if you're tight on a budget definitely
go after an adjustable kettle bell
system and then let's say you want you
know your kettle bells to be uniform in
size well you're not going to get that
with any cast iron kettle bell so
definitely go after some competition
kettle bells if that's what you're
looking
for that's all I got for youall today on
the Nike kettle bells while these are
not my personal favorites if you're a
big fan of Nike or maybe May you're just
looking for you know some affordable
kettle bells then these will probably
get the job done for you thanks for
hanging out with me all' I hope this
video was helpful and I hope that I was
able to answer any questions you may
have about these kettle bells as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barb. comom cuz we have
a full written article about these
kettle bells that you might find to be
really helpful all you got to do is
search barbend Nike kettle bell review
that article is going to pull right up
for you you can go over every single
thing we talked about here today I'll
catch youall next time
[Music]